当前是1945年8月6日上午8:14，而你即将要经历地狱。
It's 8:14 am on August 6, 1945, and you’re about to live through hell.
但是此刻，辉煌，晴朗的一天才刚刚开始。
But for now, a brilliant, clear day is getting started.
经历了早交峰和拥挤的轨电，你便可以在宽敞，现代的办公楼
Morning traffic and crowded streetcars go by, and you arrive at work--a large, modern
上班了。
office building.
早些时候，响起了一个空袭警报，但就目前来说响起警报已经很屡见不鲜了，
Earlier in the morning, there was an air raid alarm, but by now those are so common that
他们几乎就是在例行公事一般。
they hardly register as more than routine.
此外，解除警报也表明了这一点。
And besides, the all clear has come through.
只发现了几架飞机，意味着这可能不是轰炸。
Only a few planes were spotted, meaning this likely wasn't a bombing run.
没有迹象表明今天会是非同寻常的一天。
There's no real reason to believe that this day would be any worse than the last.
日本的其他城市，尤其是东京，受到炸弹的严重打击。
Other Japanese cities, notably Tokyo, have taken serious hits from bombing.
但是到目前为止，你的城市广岛还是比较幸运的，就像是被
But so far, your city, Hiroshima, has been comparatively fortunate--all but ignored by
美国的B-29轰炸机忽略了。
the American B-29s.
日本进行了十多年的全面战争以不同方式影响了日本的每个人。
The total warfare Japan has been waging for over a decade has affected everyone in the
在年轻的时候，你就自己在国外服务过。
country in some way--when you were younger, you'd served overseas yourself.
现在，这些年过去了，让人惊讶的是，你竟然能幸免于后方阵线的
Now, all these years later, it's almost surprising that you've been spared the worst tragedies
最糟糕的惨剧。
of the home front.
最重要的是，你祈祷战争会在你儿子年纪大到可以打仗，或者
Most of all, you pray that the war will end before your son is old enough to fight, or
女儿将要丧偶之前结束。
daughter to be widowed.
现在如其他的年轻人，他们一直忙于民防，
For now, like the other teenagers, they've been occupied with civilian defense, helping
在发生入侵时协助拆除旧建筑物，为军事战车腾出空间。
knock down old buildings to make way for military vehicles in the event of an invasion.
一分钟后：上午8:15。
A minute later: 8:15 am.
你走进了办公楼的大厅。
You step into the lobby of the building.
然后世界都改变了。
And then the world changes.
难以置信的黄光就像你被正在拍照的相机的闪光灯包围一样，
An incredible yellow light like the flash from a camera blazes all around you, and everything
你眼前的一切都是空白。
around you becomes an empty white.
你腾空了，你感受到碎片击中你，接着是震耳欲聋的
You're sent flying, and you feel pieces of debris strike you, followed by the deafening
爆炸声响起。
boom as the sound from the explosion catches up.
你猛然摔倒在地板上并失去意识，有可能只是片刻，你也不确定。
You slam against the floor and lose consciousness–probably just for a moment, you're not sure.
你清楚你需要站起来。
You know you need to get up.
你伤到骨头了吗？
Did you break any bones?
没时间考虑这种情况。
No time to consider the situation.
大厅里没有其他人，但是所有家具和你自己
No one else is in the lobby with you, but all of the furniture has been blown to one
都被炸到了房间的一侧。
side of the room, along with your body.
你支起自己，然后走出外面的门，门上也没有了上面的
You push yourself up and step back outside through the door that's now missing all of
玻璃。
its glass.
你检查了自己周围，看看到底发生了什么。
You check all around yourself, and see what you're up against.
在你面前是一堵火墙，它似乎正在增长。
In front of you is a wall of fire, and it seems to be growing.
你转身向反方向跑，但是狂风在阻碍着你，玻璃和
You turn to run the other way, but now the wind is against you, and the glass shards
瓦砾碎片在你所感受到过的最强大的风暴中飞向大火。
and pieces of rubble fly back toward the blaze in the most powerful storm you've ever felt.
你躲回门口，看着任何可能着火的东西。
You duck back into the doorway and watch as anything that can catch fire, does.
就这样，你将不得不抗击如此巨大的风暴。
Somehow, you'll have to fight the tremendous windstorm.
在向前推进时，你会瞥见爆炸期间曾在屋外的人，
As you push forward, you catch glimpses of people who'd been outside during the blast,
有一些躺在街上，已经死了。
some lying dead in the street.
指尖是身体着火的第一部分。
The fingertips are the first part of the body to catch fire.
在活着的人中，有些被严重烧死。
Among the living, some are horribly burned.
炽热的风将衣服粘带着皮肤，一条条的吹走。
The boiling wind blows strips of clothing off of them, along with strips of skin.
每个人都只是想远离火源。
Everyone just wants to get away from the fire.
你感觉自己也可能会被烧死。
You feel like you might be getting burned yourself.
你面前有条河。
There's the river in front of you.
随着一群人在后面向你施压，你跳入水中。
Along with the pack of people pressing against you, you jump into the water.
当你浮出水面喘口气的时候，更多的碎屑像下雨一样落下。
When you rise above the surface to catch your breath, more debris rains down.
多少时间过去了？
How much time has passed?
还会有更多炸弹吗？
Are more bombs falling?
你听到一个孩子大喊大叫，然后帮助她越到河的另一边。
You hear a child yelling, and help her get across to the other side of the river.
还好没有更多的炸弹，尽管有四面八方的大火在燃烧，但是火球
There are no more bombs, and although there are fires burning in all directions, the fireball
停止扩张，空气也不是那么热了。
has stopped expanding, and the air isn't as hot.
你尝试帮助人们站起来。
You try to help people to their feet.
有些可以，有些则不能。
Some can manage, others can't.
一辆消防车到了，人们开始搀扶那些不能走上卡车的人。
A fire engine arrives, and the men start pulling anyone who can't walk onto the truck.
你会尽力提供帮助，然后和一小群幸免于难的人
You help as best you can, and then follow in the direction that the truck heads, along
按照卡车行驶的方向前进。
with a small cohort of other people who've escaped the worst of the blast.
现在，当你徒步穿越成堆的砖块，混凝土和金属，
Now, as you trek through piles of bricks, concrete, and metal, making your way back
朝着你的房子前进时，云层变厚，大雨滴落下。
toward your house, the cloud cover thickens, and heavy drops of rain fall.
它们是黑色的，显然是辐射尘造成的。
They're black, apparently from soot.
对你来说，没有什么比先确定家人的安全更重要，但无论你
Nothing is as important to you as finding out if your family is safe, but neither you
还是其他的幸存者，在经过一个个被大火和浓烟包围，被夷为平地的建筑时，
nor the other survivors can ignore the calls for help as you pass block upon block of leveled
也不会忽略掉求助者的呼喊。
buildings amid the smoke and fire.
数小时以来，你在推进时通过的浓烟和残骸，还有燃烧的房屋，
For hours, as you press northward through the smoke and wreckage, and burning houses,
你会听到有人被困在建筑下的哭声。
you hear the cries of people trapped below buildings.
如果可能的话，你会从废墟中解救他们。
When you can, you free them from the debris.
还有的，你也无能为力。
Others, you're powerless to help.
你经过无数次的绊倒、爬行、匍匐或死亡。
You pass countless stumbling, crawling, prostrate, or dead.
你掩饰你的罪恶感，并尽量避免看到最坏的情况。
You bury your guilt, and try not to see the worst.
你最大程度的确认你家附近的方向并向前推进。
You press forward in what you're fairly sure is the direction of your neighborhood.
一个小女孩在徘徊，抓着头上的伤口。
A little girl is wandering, clutching at a wound on her head.
你没法忽略她，抱着她走了一英里，直到你到达一个学校
You refuse to pass her by, and for a mile you carry her, until you reach a makeshift
内部的临时诊所，这里除了窗户外，基本上还完好无损。
clinic inside a school that, aside from its windows, is largely intact.
稍后，你将了解到你是离原子弹爆炸中心最近的人却没有
Later you'll learn that you were among the closest people to the atomic blast who didn't
死。
die.
你所在的建筑物使你免受爆炸和热浪的冲击。
The building you were in shielded you from the full force of the blast and heat.
半英里之内暴露于初始高温之下的任何人都不仅仅是
Anyone within a half mile who was exposed to the initial blast of heat didn't merely
烧死，而是瞬间被焚化。
burn to death: they were instantly incinerated.
在这个半径之外，还有成千上万的人被烧死，或者死于飞起的碎片和
Outside that radius, thousands more burned to death, or died from the flying debris and
倒塌的建筑。
falling buildings.
在小学里，伤员已经肩并肩
Here in the elementary school, people are already stretched out shoulder-to-shoulder
躺在地上。
on the floor.
一些护士在人与人之间争先恐后的清理着最严重的伤口，但显然
A few nurses scramble from person to person, cleaning the worst wounds, but apparently
已经没有足够的绷带给每个人。
already without enough bandages for everyone.
一些烧焦的身体显然已经停止了呼吸。
Some of the charred bodies have clearly already stopped breathing.
市内进行着所有紧急计划，在城市的各个区域
All of the emergency planning in the city, setting up emergency aid centers with supplies
建立备有物资的紧急援助中心，都会假设在此次攻击之后
in the various sectors of the city, had assumed there would actually be a city left after
是否还有这个城市存在。
an attack.
多数成年人痛苦难忍，但从孩子们的哭声中可以明显看出
Most of the adults are stoical in their suffering, but from the cries of children, it's clear
已经没什么止痛药了。
that there's little medicine for the pain.
当你扫描垫子上难以置信，不同程度损伤的身（尸）体时，但求希望不要看到
As you scan the unbelievable ranks of bodies on the mats, desperately hoping not to see
任何认识的人，你可以看到他们受伤的全部情况。
anyone familiar, you see the full extent of their injuries.
许多人被烧得如此惨烈，以至于你都无法想象他们会幸存下来。
Many are so badly burned you can't imagine that they'll survive.
显然，穿深色衣服比穿着白色衣服的人更容易
Apparently, people who were wearing dark colored clothing were sometimes burned more than those
被烧伤，因为吸收热量的差异。
wearing white, because of the difference in heat absorption.
伴随着无法控制的解脱的泪水，你知道这里面没有自己的家人。
With uncontrollable tears of relief, you learn that no one in your own family is among them.
距离市中心三英里，你家的木屋被毁，
Three miles from miles from the center of the city, your family's wooden house was destroyed,
但尚未起火，至少现在还未起火。
but hadn't caught fire, at least not yet.
你感到恐惧，你意识到自己的妻子正在流血，背面和侧面都被玻璃碎片
You're frightened when you realize that your wife has been bleeding, cut down her back
割伤，但她向你保证，切口全伤在表面，
and sides by glass shards, but she assures you that the injuries are all on the surface,
她牵着你的手，找到你儿子和女儿，他们都在想方设法的
and takes you by the hand, to your son and daughter, both of whom are trying to administer
对伤者进行一些帮助。
some aid to the wounded.
没有实际的药膏了，不得不使用食用油来代替，
There's no actual ointment left, and they're making due with cooking oil, which is better
尽管让人不安，但基于现在的情况，总比什么都没有好。
than nothing, albeit disturbing, given what's happened.
孩子们都遭受了擦伤和割伤，但是他们最大的痛苦就是等着你回来。
They've both suffered bruises and cuts, but their greatest pain was waiting for you to
回来吧。
return.
他们比较确信，因为你在市中心上班，你也一定没能幸存。
They'd been certain that since you were in the city center, you must have been killed.
但对你而言，你很高兴还能看着他们健康的
For your part, you're glad you've been able to keep your children healthy as they've
成长。
grown up.
随着配给的不足，诊所中的其他年轻人变得虚弱，
Other young people at the clinic have become weak as the rationing has gotten worse,
并且你会看到，在伤者中，营养不足将使他们生存的
and you can see that among the injured, malnutrition is going to
可能性要小得多。
make their chances of survival much less likely.
现在你已经找到了家人，你可以回去帮助救援。
Now that you've found your family, you can go back out and help with the rescue.
除了持续的撤离队伍，你看不到有组织的协助，但是
You can't see much organized effort beyond the continuing lines of evacuees, but along
与其他个体一起，你尽可能的帮助更多的伤员撤离。
with other individuals, you try to move as many of the injured as you can.
一些伤者卡在了河边的沙洲上，而你在涨潮之前将他们抬到
Some wounded people are stuck on a sandbar by the river, and you help to lift them to
更高的地面。
higher ground before the tide rises.
这期间有一个特别惊悚的状况，伤者的身体从你的手中滑落，
In one particularly gruesome instance, the body of a victim slips from your hands as
因为烧伤的手臂皮肤过于松弛。
the burned skin of the arm tears loose.
又过几个小时后，你开始感到虚弱，然后回到援助站。
After several more hours, you begin feeling weak, and wander back to the aid station.
当你到达那里时，你不禁意识到，不管骨头骨折与否，
By the time you get there, you realize that, broken bones or no,
你并没有毫发无损。你不可能只是精疲力尽。
you haven't escaped unharmed. It can't just be exhaustion catching up with you.
你感到头晕目眩，感觉很无力，就像感染了流感一样。
You're lightheaded, and feel weak, like you've come down with the flu.
你坐在一张简易床上，只为了喘口气。
You sit down on a cot, just to catch your breath.
你感觉像是发烧了。
You feel feverish.
护士给了你一杯水，你很感激。
A nurse offers a cup of water, which you gratefully accept.
但当你将凉爽的液体倒在嘴唇上时，你却无法咽下去。
But as you pour the cool liquid past your lips, you can't swallow it.
窘迫，你咳嗽然后吐出来。
Embarrassed, you cough and spit it out.
突然，你感到更糟，并且毫无犹豫地开始呕吐到地板上。
You feel much worse all of a sudden, and without hesitation begin to vomit on the floor.
有人把废纸篓放在你面前去接住呕吐物。
Someone puts a wastebasket next to you to catch it.
你不是首个出现这种症状的人，也不会单单一个人继续干呕
You weren't the first with this symptom, nor will you be alone as you continue to retch
并且连续几天腹泻下去。
and suffer diarrhea for days on end.
援助人员正在分发柔软的大米饼干和稀饭，但跟你一样，
Aid workers are distributing soft rice biscuits and bowls of rice porridge, but, like you,
很多人都没有食欲。
many people have little appetite.
随着时间的流逝，虫类嗅探到幸存者身上坏死的组织。
As days pass, insects find the necrotic tissue on the survivors.
受惊的家庭成员则会尽力清理有幼虫的伤口。
Horrified family members do their best to clear the wounds of larvae.
你感到尴尬去让你的妻子和孩子照顾你。
You're embarrassed to have your wife and children caring for you.
本应该是相反的方式。
It's supposed to be the other way around.
经过几天的痛苦，恶心感消退了。
After a couple of days of misery, the nausea subsides.
怎么不呢？
How could it not?
你好几天没吃饭了。
You haven't eaten in days.
这需要勇气，但你可以抿一小口水，然后喝一两口
It takes courage, but you're able to take tiny sips of water, and then a bite or two
稀粥。
of porridge.
很少有时间和医生独处，但是从你无意听到的情况来看，你被侵入了一种
It's rare to get a moment with a doctor, but from what you can overhear, you've been hit
叫做γ（伽玛）射线的无形之力所引起的疾病，它可以直接
with sickness caused by an invisible kind of force called gamma rays that can fly right
穿过你的身体，撕开你的组织。
through your body, ripping tissues apart.
随着力量的恢复，你再次尝试使自己变得有用起来，去帮助完成
As your strength recovers, you again try to make yourself useful
无休止的重建工作。
aiding in the endless recovery work.
通常，这意味着帮助将尸体运送到火葬场。
Often that means helping to carry bodies to the perpetual funeral pyres.
这些不幸者中的许多人从未与家人道别
Many of these unfortunates never got to say goodbye to their families, and their loved
他们的爱人也永远不会知道自己丈夫的遗骸变成了什么。
ones will never know what became of their remains.
对于某些伤者而言，辐射中毒更加严重。
For some victims, the poisoning from radiation was much worse.
接近24小时大关，有几个因大脑受损而变得语无伦次。
By the 24 hour mark, several had become incoherent from damage to the brain.
有些人心跳加速，一些不久便心脏病发作。
Others had a racing heart; some soon suffered a heart attack.
一些则从实际上发生了颜色变化，变成了鲜红色，就像被晒伤一样。
Some literally changed color, turning bright red as if sunburned.
与你不同的是，受过辐射毒害，没有恢复食欲的人则在几天内就死了。
Those who, unlike you, never recovered their appetite, were dead in a few days.
但是随后，一些特别令人担忧的事情发生了。
But then something especially worrying begins.
几个已经下床的人现在又平躺在床上，
Several people who had been up and about are now again lying flat on the cots, and they
他们看上去很不好。
don't look good.
随着血管破裂，他们的皮肤变得斑驳，有紫色斑点。
Their skin has become mottled with purple blotches as blood vessels break.
他们会再次感到虚弱和不适。
Again they feel weak and sick.
痛苦看起来已经难以承受，但随后变得更加严重。
The pain already looks like too much to bear, but then it gets worse.
垂死的呕吐着鲜血，血液从他们的肛门中流出。
The dying vomit blood, and blood flows from their anus.
甚至眼睛也开始流血。
Even the eyes begin to bleed.
到目前为止，更多的医务人员已经从市郊和县外加入。
By now additional medical workers have come from the outskirts and outside the prefecture.
但是那些徘徊在死亡边缘的人往往会静脉萎缩，因此他们甚至无法注射
But those who hover over death tend to have shriveled veins, so they can't even receive
吗啡。
morphine.
你希望不要步入他们的后尘。
You hope that you're not due to follow their downward slide.
医生会对你进行检查，并发现你身体上被忽视的斑点。
A doctor examines you, and notices spots on your body that you'd overlooked.
状况还是发生了。
It's happening.
但是至少现在你还没有感觉到，并且可以进行对话。
But at least for now you don't feel it, and you're able to carry on a conversation.
医生来自东京。
The doctor has come from Tokyo.
他准是这种疾病的专家，尽管在广岛和
He must be an expert on this kind of disease, although before the bombing of Hiroshima
长崎爆炸之前，只有极少数的病例。
and Nagasaki, there were very few cases
大多数科学家只是用镭或其他非寻常物质进行研究。
mostly scientists doing research with radium or other unusual substances.
他确认核弹爆炸给你带来了有害的辐射。
He confirms that the atomic bomb blast dosed you with harmful radiation.
在这段对话，以及接下来的许多年中，你将热衷于了解辐射相关的
In that conversation, and many more that would follow over the years, you avidly learn details
详细信息。
about radiation.
爆炸会发出了γ（伽马）射线，也发出X射线。
The blast did emit gamma rays, and X-rays as well.
它们略有不同，但主要需知的是，在足够高的强度下，
They're slightly different, but the main thing to know is that in a high enough strength,
它们都对你非常有害，不像医生使用的相对较弱的X射线
they're both very bad for you, unlike the relatively weak X-rays that doctors use to
用来给你的骨头呈像。
take pictures of your bones.
X射线和γ（伽马）射线都是由光子构成的，光子和普通光束是
Both X-rays and gamma rays are made of photons, the same kind of wave-particle as regular
同一种波粒子。
beams of light.
但就人们而言。它们的波长要短得多，
But they have a much shorter wavelength, and very different properties from visible light,
而且与可见光的特性大不相同。
as far as people are concerned.
相比之下，一些从严重灼伤中恢复过来的人，
By comparison, some of the people who are recovering from serious burns to the skin
同样也收到了非常大量的长波红外辐射
also received a very, very heavy amount of long wavelength, infrared radiation, which
会导致物质升温-但如果是短波辐射的情况，则是非常严重的。
causes matter to heat up--in this case, a great deal.
爆炸的温度是几千度-足以顷刻间使人
The temperature of the blast was thousands of degrees--enough to reduce people to dust
化成灰烬。
in an instant.
尽管γ（伽玛）射线不会引起表面灼伤，但它们是所谓电离辐射的
Although gamma rays don't cause surface burns, they're an example of what's called ionizing
一个例子。
radiation.
非电离辐射，例如无线电天线接收到的信号，
Non-ionizing radiation, like the signals that a radio antenna picks up, doesn't seem to
在日常程度下似乎对活体组织没有太大影响。
have much effect of living tissue at everyday doses.
但是电离辐射是另一回事。
But ionizing radiation is another story.
它的的名称正来自于其无形的作用，即导致分子内的原子失去电子，
This class gets its name from its invisible effect, which is to cause an atom to lose
留下带正电的阳离子（正原子核）。
electrons, leaving positively charged ions.
人体细胞内部是由电子结合在一起的复杂分子，并且
Inside the cells of your body are complex molecules held together by electrons, and
如果足够多的分子被撕裂，细胞就会死亡。
if enough of the molecules are torn apart, the cell dies.
当它发生在骨髓时，会尤其可怕，因为骨髓为身体
This is especially bad when it happens in bone marrow, which manufactures blood cells
制造血液。
for the body.
红细胞的缺乏会使人体缺氧。
白细胞浓度低则使身体易受感染。
血小板太少会阻止血液凝结，这会导致特征性斑点（淤斑、紫癜）
以及其他不良影响。
除了γ（伽玛）射线和X射线，还有一种称为β射线的电子流，
In addition to gamma and X-rays, there are streams of particles called beta rays, which
是松散的电子。
are loose electrons.
随着不稳定物质的衰变，由氦带电原子核和松散中子组成的α射线
Alpha rays, the charged nuclei of helium atoms, and loose neutrons, fly out of unstable elements
会从这些不稳定元素中飞出。
as they decay.
几磅这种铀（放射性物质）元素就是广岛原子弹的核燃料。
A few pounds of one such element, uranium, was the fuel for the atom bomb at Hiroshima.
另一种是钚，驱动了长崎原子弹爆炸。
Another, plutonium, powered the blast at Nagasaki.
事实证明，这两种元素在产生核链式反应方面都非常有效。
Both elements proved terribly effective at creating a chain reaction.
而且，在任何时间段内没有保护措施的处理这些物质
Moreover, it's not safe to even handle much of these substances for any length of time
都是不安全的。
without protection.
玛丽·居里（居里夫人）发现了许多重要的放射性物质的特性
Marie Curie, who had discovered many of the important properties of radioactivity had
她自己后来死于辐射中毒（恶性白血病）。
herself later died of radiation poisoning.
因此，在核爆炸产生的烟雾和尘埃中，有大量放射性粒子
So amid the smoke and dust from the nuclear explosion was a mass of radioactive particles
吹向空中。
blasted into the air.
一些核物质在黑雨中掉了下来。
Some of that material fell right back down in the black rain.
如果你的皮肤或衣服上有放射性物质，你会将其散布在周围。
If you have radioactive material on your skin or clothes you can spread it around.
更糟的是，如果你摄入放射性尘埃，它会在你的系统中停留一段时间，并且
Worse, if you ingest radioactive dust, it can stay in your system for some time, and
至少有一段时间，你的身体本身可能会发出辐射。
for awhile at least, your body could itself give off radiation.
想想你是怎么抱着你的妻子和孩子的，现在真希望你没有这么快
You think about how you held your wife and children, and now wish you hadn't found them
找到他们。
so quickly.
由于爆炸离地面很高，市中心没有极点危险区。
Because the blast was so far above ground, there wouldn't be a dangerous concentration
混乱中的一点小安慰。
at the center--one small comfort in the chaos.
数周以来，你的健康状况会下降。
For weeks, you do decline in health.
你这次住进了真正的医院。
You're admitted to a real hospital this time.
你的头发全部脱落，并且皮肤变得肿胀。
All your hair falls out, and your skin becomes swollen.
恶心又回来了。
The nausea comes back.
人们继续死亡。
People continue to die.
到9月，一些烧伤者的状况有所好转。
By September, some of the burn victims are in better shape.
你认为那些有严重烧伤且辐射中毒的人现在已经死了。
You assume that those with both heavy burns and radiation poisoning are dead by now.
但是你还活着。
But you do not die.
这些年来，你的家人建立了新的生活，非常感谢你没有和
Over the years, your family builds a new life, utterly thankful that you didn't share the
两个被摧毁的城市中的超过20万的死者的命运一样。
fate of more than 200,000 in the two devastated cities.
你重新工作一段时间，然后退休。
You return to work for some time, and then retire on a pension.
你的儿子和女儿都结婚了，并且都开始建立自己的家庭。
Your son and daughter both marry, and each begins to build their own family.
你了解到体内一种称为DNA的特殊化学物质，科学家所发现的
You learn about a special kind of chemical in the body called DNA, which scientists have
它包含你体内所有细胞设计的蓝图，并与你爱人的DNA
found contains all the blueprints for the cells in your body, and that combines with
结合在一起，将在子宫内孕育一个新的生命。
the DNA from your spouse to build a new person in a woman's womb.
你还了解到DNA损伤会导致癌症，并且你知道癌症发生率
You also learn that it's damage to DNA that causes cancer, and you know that cancer rates
对于受到过辐射的人来说尤其高。
are especially high for people exposed to radiation.
你比较担心自己的孩子。
You're not worried so much for yourself as for your children.
尽管他们可能没有表现出急性放射病，但他们肯定受到了γ（伽马）射线
Although they may not have displayed acute radiation sickness, they were certainly exposed
的照射。
to gamma rays.
如果DNA受损，他们的孩子可能不会继承突变的基因吗？
And if DNA is damaged, might their children not have inherited the mutated genes?
肯定的是，爆炸后不久出生的一些婴儿的缺陷率很高，
Certainly, some babies born soon after the bombing had a high rate of birth defects,
例如大脑发育不全。
like underdeveloped brains.
到目前为止，还没有人看到任何遗传性损伤遗传给Hibakusha的孩子（爆二代）的证据。
So far, no one has seen any evidence of genetic damaged passed on to children of hibakusha.
Hibakusha（爆炸幸存者群体）-即在子宫内未接受直接照射的幸存者。
atom bomb survivors，who weren't exposed in utero.
你要确保你的孩子以及他们的孩子得到医生的检查，崭新的，
You make sure that your children and theirs get check-ups from the doctor, and the new,
更和平的日本政府会密切关注他们的健康，当然还有你的。
more peaceful Japanese government is keeping tabs on their health, and yours of course.
你不禁会注意到东京新街区的邻居不想和你的家人
You can't help but notice that people in your new neighborhood in Tokyo don't want to stand
靠的太近，尽管他们的恐惧是没有根据的，但你可以理解
close to anyone in your family, and although their fears are unfounded, you can understand
他们在如此陌生的时代的谨慎。
their wariness in such strange times.
你关注着军备竞赛的发展，各国制造的核武器可造成的破坏
And you follow the arms race, as nations build nuclear weapons that could somehow inflict
可能比你所经历的要大的多。
far more damage than the one you experienced.
数年后，你带着子孙去看电影。
Years later, you take your grandchildren to see a movie you've heard about.
在这部电影中，有一个爬行动物，其身体受辐射改变，变成了一个
In this movie, there's a reptile whose body is altered by radiation, turning it into a
摧毁东京市的怪物。
monster that destroys the city of Tokyo.
你知道这有点戏剧性，但这就是电影的目的。
It's a bit of dramatic license, you know, but that's what movies are for.
孩子们已经足够大了，他们尽量不显得害怕，但很明显会原子吐息的怪兽
The kids are old enough that they try not to seem scared, although clearly the fire-breathing
还是给他们留下了深刻的印象。
beast makes quite an impression on them.
尽管您决定不与新时代的这些孩子分享影片中的寓意，
The allegory in the movie is not lost on you, although you decide not to share it with these
但您并不会因此忘怀。
children of a new era.
孩子们也意识到他们的国家发动战争的痛苦和愚蠢的经历，以及
They're aware of their country's bitter, foolish experience in making war, and the awful toll
他们的父母在测试人类苦难极限时所目睹的可怕的伤亡。
that their parents witnessed when men tested the limits of human suffering.
但是您衷心希望他们自己只会在电影中
But you hope with all your heart that they will themselves only ever see such horror
看到这种恐怖。
in a movie.
这个故事由广岛幸存者的第一手资料合成并讲述。
你知道有人因为工作或医疗，或是接触有害物质而
不得不面对严重的辐射吗？
请在评论中让我们知道你的想法。
Let us know what you think in the comments.
另外，请务必查看我们的其他视频“如果有核武器
Also, be sure to check out our other video called “What To Do If There’s a Nuclear
爆炸该怎么办”
Explosion.”
感谢你的收看，一如既往，不要忘记喜欢，分享和订阅。
Thanks for watching, and, as always, don’t forget to like, share, and subscribe.
下期见！
See you next time!